左？　来い！ うっ!?
He abandoned you when you were still just a baby.
フクロウの羽？　クソっ！
He was willing to abandon his own kid for it.
コウモリの羽音で フクロウのほうは全然聞こえない
That's how amazing it is to be a Hunter!
テレパシー
You want to climb the tree?
テレパシー いいえ　逆にチャンス！
No one under the age of eighteen
can go beyond this point.
テレパシー 恐らく　あれが奴の必殺技 看破すれば　私達の勝利！ テレパシー
Unless you have some special
license or certification...
テレパシー 待って　なるべく静かに 近づいてみるわ。
A pro Hunter? At your age?
音が遠ざかる
Go right ahead. But I'll need you to sign this first.
音が消えた！ 羽ばたかずに…
It's just the usual thing that says you
don't care if you die during the climb.
動かない？　ウフフっ しょせんは人間の聴力ね ならば　このまま攻撃
Here's some advice! Don't trust any of the grips or footholds
left behind by previous climbers.
頸動脈をぶち切ってやる！
Those who make it to the top
usually do it bare-handed.
動きは最小限に 最大まで引きつけてから
That's how the guy who's at
the top right now did it.
けど　ここから奴のパンチが 来るまでの　０コンマ数秒
Well, if you feel you're in trouble,
just press that button.
余裕で空中へ回避できる ハァ…！
Our rescue team is skilled.
わっ!!
If you can hold on to the tree for ten minutes—
ぐっ　音が…　見えない
He fell?! Hey!
とにかく回避よ！
Hey!
音で位置が分かるのは… ケン！
He's already up there?
クソっ！　技まで出したのに 仕留め損なった！
I still have a long way to go...
ばかデカい声 出しやがって　クソガキが。
This tree is incredible.
だけど　音での攻撃は 私のほうが何枚も上手よ！
I can entrust myself to it.
これが奴らの 真のコンビネーション 音で刺し　力でとる フフフ…　どうする？
The moment my fingers touch it, I can feel that there's life there, and that it flows throughout the entire tree.
この闇の中　音が聞けなきゃ 反応が　かなり鈍る
I can do this!
そうだ！　「凝」！ ん？
So long as I heed the tree's whispering as I climb...
ぐっ！
Help me...
「絶」 そうか　こいつら もともと野生の生物
Almost there.
天性の技術！ 何とか耐えられる
The top looks funny.
それを崩さなきゃ！
They're huge!
テレパシー なるほど 小生にピッタリ接近すれば
That scared me...
テレパシー 甘いわね！
Hi!
けど　コウモリには逃げられて 仲間に知らされる危険が高い
Yo.
ゴホホホ　星の出ている夜なら 小生にとって昼と同じ！
I was tired of waiting.
真の闇でなければ 聴覚を使わずとも
Ging...
お前の姿は　ハッキリと 見えるのであります！ 従って 小生は耳をふさぎまして…
How long did it take you to get
here from the 500-meter point?
私は出しまくり！
Uh... Around twenty minutes?
ガキは全身　まんべんなく オーラで覆っている
Well, I guess that's acceptable for your first time... Eat up.
そのせいで かなり攻撃力が落ちて
Yep!
そんなんじゃ　いつまで戦っても ２人は倒せねえぜ こいつはダメかもな
Beautiful view, right?
こいつらの弱点　それは
On overcast days, it's like a sea of clouds. Yeah!
完全統制された コンビネーション！
Hey, Ging...
ここだ！
Can I ask you something?
奴らは２匹が同時に 狙われないよう
Sure. I might not give you an answer, though.
必ず対極に位置をとる
What is it that you want?
ふぬ！ コウモリは真後ろ！ うっ　あっ！
That which I can't see in front of me right now.
巨大な壁？
That which you can't see in front of you?
１匹なら　攻撃に専念できるぞ。
I wanted to become a Hunter because, at the time, it was the most practical way
だが　その程度の攻撃力じゃ ここでは　お話にならねえぜ
That place was used as a certain
royal family's burial ground.
クソっ！ ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。 最初は　グ！
To enter, you had to belong to
a trustworthy organization, and to agree never to speak of it.
ジャン！　ケン！ このっ！
And you had to pay all expenses out of pocket.
グ!! おぉ！
In other words, you couldn't really explore it at all.
そっちが西なのも計算済み！
You won't find anyone willing to spend
ＮＧＬまで　飛んでけっ！ すっげぇ威力！
the resources and receive nothing in return.
なるほど こっちが奴の必殺技か
But I saw it as my chance.
前言撤回　使えるなぁ 問題は　どうやって…
If I became a trusted pro Hunter, getting the money wouldn't be a problem.
他の村や町も　洗脳された兵士が 国民を殺して回っているんだ！
When I turned fifteen, I set up a special nonprofit organization to explore and repair the tomb.
ディーゴが失脚？ 本当か？
Before that, I'd spent the two
years after getting my license
だが　この兵士達が 虐殺を始めたのは事実！ 迷ってる暇はないぞ！ どこでもいい　村を出ろ！
surfing archaeology buffs' websites and blogs online.
そして　このことを 他の地区の人達にも 知らせてくれ！
To create the nonprofit, I needed about ten oddballs
人形の動きが封じられた…
who didn't need money or fame,
but only wanted to know the truth, and who could be trusted to keep secrets.
行動を読まれないように 刺客？　けど　たった一人で
I'm always going after what I need.
おとり？　う
I'm so focused, I stop caring about
the ultimate goal that lies beyond.
でも　動きが誘う感じじゃ
The people I recruited online and
befriended in offline meetings
慎重に行動してるとしか そう思わせておいて
were all older than me. They were regular office workers,
graduate students, and job-hoppers.
答えの出ない問いに溺れて
After I told them my background and plan, they helped with the various tasks
to create the nonprofit, and they even gave donations
from what little money they had.
それだけのこと。
When our dream was realized and
we stepped inside for the first time, the best part for me
それ以外のことは　他の者に
wasn't when I finally witnessed the truth of the tomb.
出番ですね。
at my colleagues' faces and shook their hands.
今こそ　このレオル 恩返しする時！ 僕の人形を止めて回ってる 奴がいるんだ。
To this day, they still work for the
nonprofit with zero compensation, providing me with viable information.
殺っちゃってくれる？ お任せください。
The secret of the tomb
ケータイ　持ってって。
was nothing compared to the relationships I built.
僕らは テレパシー使えないから そいつの現在地は 随時　それに連絡するから。 はっ。
What was truly important came
to me before what I wanted.
あわよくば 寝首をかこうと虎視眈々。
And now? Huh?
フッ…　それならば　それ相応に 扱ってやればいいだけのこと。
What are you after now? Right now? It'll take some time to explain...
ハァ　ハァ…。 ここから一番近い町は ２時の方向
Gon, what is this tree we just climbed? Huh? It's the World Tree.
次が８時　１０時
That's right.
全部とばして　まず ４０ｋｍ先のタバ市まで行くか
Down below, how did they describe the tree?
慎重に 絶対に見つからないように！
At 1,784 meters, it's the world's tallest tree.
やっぱ　こっちは　やめだ
is a young sapling that's stopped growing.
すげぇスピードで ヂートゥって野郎が
A real World Tree
東ゴルトーへ向かってやがる。 後任のハンターが 捕まえ損ねたに違いねえ。
would take in magma, embed its roots in the mountains, and continue to grow after leaving the atmosphere.
いや　このままだと はるか南を通過する。 どこへ行く気だ？
Outside this world.
止めても行くぜ。
This world?
こっちゃ ただでさえ　ムカムカ来てんだ。
The world map that you're familiar with.
その中に師団長は　いなかった。
The Ants that you and the chairman fought
コルトによると 好戦的な師団長が　あと８匹いる。
were a non-native species from outside this world.
その中の４匹は ハンターが遭遇していたのに
That's the truth they don't teach you in school.
結局　逃げられちまってるんだ。
Adults with common sense
ヂートゥが東ゴルトーを目指してるのは やみくもじゃ　ねえ。 王がこっちに来たことを 知ってるからだ！
choose not to go near Pandora's Box.
地力も俺の方が上だ。 だが　このまま見過ごして
In other words, the world that we know
奴が　さらに強力な能力を得たら 勝負は全く分からなくなる。
is nothing but a small part of a much bigger world.
そんな連中が何匹も現れて 王の側近になってみろ　コラ！ 護衛軍を王から 引き離すどころじゃねえぞ！ それでも止めるか？ あぁ？　コラ。 なら　まず　てめぇをやるぞ。
There are records showing that a chosen few, from a select time and place,
were able to make it outside.
ん？
Understand now?
万が一の場合　俺達の代わりを
I still want the same thing I always have.
探してもらわなければ ならないからな。 俺も行くよ。
Something that I can't see in front of me.
で　あの…　もしもし？　もしもし？ [TEL]
There are many requirements to go outside.
バカな！ だから　あれほど リァッケを推しただろうが！
At least four are required before
you can even start the journey.
あいつ以上の 適任者なんて　いねえ！ あぁ？　んなこたぁ聞いてねえよ！ [TEL]
Authorization, the means, qualification, a contract.
どうしました？ 俺達がマークしておいた アリに逃げられたんだ。
I still haven't obtained a single one.
審査部の奴ら
But I'm in no rush.
こっちが推薦しておいた ハンターを使わなかった！
I'm enjoying the journey.
聞いたこともねえ奴だ！ どうせ「協専」だろ。
So if our paths happen to cross in the future...
「協専」…。 ハンター協会が斡旋する仕事だけを 専門とするハンターですか。
You should enjoy the little detours. To the fullest.
技量が落ちるのは当然ですね。
Because that's where you'll find the things
クソっ！　やっぱり直接 リァッケに話をつけりゃよかった。 バカなこと　言わないで下さい。
more important than what you want.
審査部の頭が固いのは　今に 始まったことじゃないでしょう。
Oh! Ging...
よく　そんな 悠長に構えてられるな！
Here.
師団長クラスをナメてたら 痛い目　見るぜ。
Kite asked me to return this to you.
奴ら　強いぜ。
Oh, okay.
手遅れになる。 まっ　それが奴らの 望みかも知れねえけどな。
The scar's still on my shoulder.
副会長派の連中が 審査部を抱き込んでいる
See? Right here.
…って噂のことを 言ってるんですか？ 次期会長選挙の票集めのため
And then, there was a huge boom!
副会長への投票に応じた ハンターにだけ 仕事を回してるってやつね…。
And what popped out was
another coffin, just this big.
何の証拠もない臆測でしょう？ ハハっ！ あいつらが尻尾を出すタマかよ！
They're called the Testing Gates,
and you have to open them to go inside.